Register of the John O. Koehler papers
Hoover Institution Archives
John O. Koehler papers
1934-2008
2001C75
Hoover Institution Archives
74 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 3 card file boxes (31.1 linear feet)
Correspondence, news dispatches and news stories, photocopies of East German secret police documents, photocopies of United States government documents, post-reunification German governmental reports, clippings, other printed matter, photographs, sound recordings, and video tapes, relating to political conditions in Germany, the East German secret police, the attempted assassination of Pope John Paul II, and Soviet espionage within the Catholic Church. In part, used as research material for the books by J. O. Koehler, Stasi: The Untold Story of the East German Secret Police (Boulder, Colo., 1999), and Spies in the Vatican: The Soviet Union's War against the Catholic Church (2009).
Koehler, John O.
Access
Collection is open for research. The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2001
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Location of Originals
This collection contains photocopies of documents in the Bundesbeauftragte für die Unterlagen des Staatssicherheitsdienstes der ehemaligen Deutschen Demokratischen Republik (BStU) and the United States National Archives and Records Administration.
Biographical Note
June 11, 1930 Born, Dresden, Germany
1950-1951 Freelance newsman for McGraw Hill Publications, Overseas Weekly, and Associated Press in Germany.
1951-1952 Sub-editor and reporter for Frankfurt bureau of Reuters.
1952 Reporter for The Canadian Press, Vancouver, WA.
1952-1953 Reporter for United Press Association and British United Press, covering Vancouver, Winnipeg, and Seattle.
1953-1954 Covered, wrote and edited local news for the Anacortes American (Washington).
1954-1957 Served in the United States Army and United States Army Reserve, entering the Army as a corporal and holding the rank of captain when discharged. Assignments included intelligence collection, counter intelligence, criminal investigation, and public affairs.
1957 Concurrent with Army service, reporter and editor for United Press Association in Phoenix, AZ.
1957-1985 AP Correspondent for 28 years, served as head of bureau in Bonn (1959-1962), chief correspondent in Berlin (1962-1965), and bureau chief for New Jersey (1965-1967). Also serves as deputy director and general manager for Personnel, and assistant general manager and managing director for the World Services Division at Associated Press headquarters in New York.
March 1987 Assistant to the President and Director of Communications under Ronald Reagan.
1999 Stasi: the Untold Story of the East German Secret Police is published by Westview Press.
July 2009 Spies in the Vatican: the Soviet Union's War Against the Catholic Church is published by Perseus Books Group.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection documents John Koehler's career as a journalist, intelligence officer, and writer; it consists of correspondence, news stories, photocopies of East German and United States government documents, post-reunification German governmental reports, clippings, printed matter, photographs, sound recordings, and videotapes. Includes papers related to the Associated Press, the U.S. Army, political conditions in Germany, espionage, and especially the East German secret police. The bulk of the papers were collected by Koehler while researching and writing his book, entitled Stasi: The Untold Story of the East German Secret Police.
The Professional Files series includes news stories written by Koehler for the Associated Press (AP) and other news organizations, many of them dating from his time as chief correspondent in Berlin, and it also includes speeches and lectures given about journalism. Additionally, the Professional Files contain a small amount of material relating to the U.S. Army, Koehler's consulting company, and his work as President Reagan's communications director. The Correspondence series records Koehler's duties at the AP, particularly after he began working in the AP administrative offices in the United States. The Photographs series is mainly composed of AP photographs from Koehler's time as a reporter, depicting escapes from East Germany as well as photographs of Koehler himself.
The Stasi Research Materials series comprises the bulk of the collection. In the course of writing Stasi: the Untold Story of the East German Secret Police, Koehler collected information from a wide variety of sources. Thus, the series includes photocopied records from the East German Ministry of State Security (MfS), interviews with former MfS officers and victims, post-reunification German government reports, photocopied documents from various United States government agencies, and an extensive subject file of clippings and published material. The series reflects Koehler's interest in MfS abuses of power and extensively documents international espionage, terrorism, and repression of the East German population during the Cold War.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into four series: Professional Files, 1946-1989; Correspondence, 1960-1997; Photographs, 1960-1979; and Stasi Research Materials, 1931-2002. The Stasi Research Material series is further divided into five subseries: German Democratic Republic State Security Ministry files, 1931-1993 [bulk 1952-1989]; Federal Republic of Germany reports, 1990-1998; United States government documents, 1943-1997; Interviews and broadcasts, 1991-1997; Subject Files, 1931-2002.
Related Material
Jürgen Perduss collection, Hoover Institution Archives
GDR Oral History Project interviews, Hoover Institution Archives
Heinrich Bortfeldt interviews, Hoover Institution Archives
Christian Joppke papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Sozialistische Einheitspartei Deutschlands miscellaneous records, Hoover Institution Archives
Appendix: Abbreviations
BF Bundesbeauftragte für die Unterlagen des Staatssicherheitsdienstes der ehemaligen Deutschen Demokratischen Republik, Abteilung Bildung und Forschung Research and education department of the Federal Commission for the Papers of the State Security Service of the former German Democratic Republic
BfgA Bundesanstalt für gesamtdeutsche Aufgaben Federal Institute for pan-German Tasks
BRD Bundesrepublik Deutschland Federal Republic of Germany (FRG)
BStU Die Bundesbeauftragte für die Unterlagen des Staatssicherheitsdienstes der ehemaligen Deutschen Demokratischen Republik Federal Commission for the Records of the State Security Service of the former German Democratic Republic
DDR Deutsche Demokratische Republik German Democratic Republic (GDR)
DKP Deutsche Kommunistische Partei German Communist Party
HA I Hauptabteilung I Chief Department I (Army)
HA II Hauptabteilung II Chief Department II (Counterintelligence)
HA III Hauptabteilung III Chief Department III (Technology and Radio)
HA V Hauptabteilung V Chief Department V (Culture, Education)
HA VII Hauptabteilung VII Chief Department VII (Prisons)
HA XVIII Hauptabteilung XVIII Chief Department XVIII (Economy/Industry)
HA XX Hauptabteilung XX Chief Department XX (Dissidents and Culture)
HA XXII Hauptabteilung XXII Chief Department XXII (Terrorism)
HVA Hauptverwaltung für Aufklärung Chief Administration for Intelligence (Foreign espionage)
IM Inoffizielle Mitarbeiter Unofficial collaborater
IMB Inoffizielle Mitarbeiter - Blickfeld Senior IM with close contact to the target
Koko Komerzielle Koordinierung Commercial Coordination (department responsible for acquiring western currency and products)
MfS Ministerium für Staatssicherheit Ministry for State Security (Stasi)
NVA Nationale Volksarmee National People's Army
OibE Offizier im besonderen Einsatz Officer in special service
ZAIG Zentrale Auswertungs- und Informationsgruppe Central evaluation and information group
ZERV Zentrale Ermittlungsstelle Regierungs- und Vereinigungskriminalität Center for discovery of governmental and reunification crimes
Germany (East) Ministerium für Staatssicherheit.; Cold War.; Espionage, East German.; Germany--Politics and government--1945-1990.; Journalists.; Phonotapes.; Photographs.; Secret service--Germany (East); Video tapes.
- Professional Files, 1946-1989.; 2.0 linear feet (Box 10-13, 51, 58)
  Scope and Contents note
  Consists of correspondence, clippings, notes, and news stories relating to Koehler's work for the U.S. Army, the Associated Press (AP), for his consulting company, and as President Reagan's communications director. Bulk of the series consists of clippings of news stories written by Koehler in the 1950s and 1960s.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged in chronological order.
  - Dutch phrase book, 1943 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Stories, 1946-1989 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Reuters Stories, 1951. (Folder 1: 3)
    Includes photographs
  - Stories, 1951-1958 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Army lesson plans, 1951-1961 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Stories, 1952-1957 (Folder 1: 6)
  - Stories, 1952-1959. (Folder 1: 7-8)
  - Stories, 1952-1964 (Folder 1: 9)
  - Stories, 1952-1967. (Folder 1: 10)
  - Stories, 1952-1975 (Folder 51: 1-12)
  - Army publications, 1955-1958. (Folder 1: 11)
  - Stories, 1956-1968 (Folder 2: 1)
  - Army Intelligence School, 1957 (Folder 2: 2)
  - Stories, 1957-1984 (Folder 2: 3)
  - Stories, 1958-1971. (Folder 2: 4-5)
  - Stories, 1959-1979 (Folder 2: 6-7)
  - Khrushchev visit to Vienna, 1960. (Folder 2: 8)
  - Stories, 1960-1963 (Folder 2: 9)
  - Stories, 1960-1964 (Folder 3: 1)
  - Stories - Russia, 1960-1967. (Folder 3: 2)
  - Stories, 1960-1980 (Folder 3: 3-12)
  - Stories, 1967-1968 (Folder 4: 1-3)
  - Army Staff College lecture, 1969-1970 (Folder 4: 4)
  - Stories, 1971 (Folder 4: 5-6)
  - Trip Reports, 1972-1973 (Folder 4: 7-8)
  - Stories - Watergate, 1973 (Folder 4: 9)
  - AP news dispatch roll, 1975 (Box 58)
  - International Narcotic Enforcement Officers Association membership certificate, 1986 (Folder 51: 1)
  - Notes, 1986 (Folder 4: 10)
  - Notes, 1987 (Folder 4: 11)
  - Clippings, 1995-1998 (Folder 4: 12)
  - Berlin slide show, undated (Folder 4: 13)
- Correspondence, 1960-1997.; 1.65 linear feet (Box 14-17)
  Includes business and personal correspondence documenting Koehler's work as a journalist and writer. Correspondence labeled personal contains both incoming and outgoing letters and documents Koehler's work managing the AP in the Personnel and World Service departments, his travels and attendance at social functions, discussions with fellow journalists, the inception of his book research. Also includes letters from victims of the Stasi.
  - Personal, 1960-1966. (Folder 5: 1)
  - Personal, 1967-1973 (Folder 5: 2-3)
  - Personal, 1968 (Folder 5: 4-5)
  - Personal, 1969 (Folder 5: 6)
  - Personal, 1970 (Folder 5: 7)
  - Personal, 1970-1971 (Folder 5: 8)
  - Personal, 1971 (Folder 5: 9)
  - Personal, 1972 (Folder 5: 10-11)
  - Personal, 1973 (Folder 5: 12)
  - Personal, 1973 (Folder 6: 1)
  - Personal, 1974 (Folder 6: 2-3)
  - Personal, 1975 (Folder 6: 4-5)
  - Personal, 1976 (Folder 6: 6)
  - Personal, 1977 (Folder 6: 7-8)
  - Personal, 1978 (Folder 6: 9-11)
  - Personal, 1979 (Folder 6: 12)
  - Personal, 1979-1980 (Folder 6: 13)
  - AP, 1981-1982. (Folder 7: 1)
  - Personal, 1981-1982 (Folder 7: 2)
  - AP, 1983 (Folder 7: 3)
  - AP, 1984 (Folder 7: 4-5)
  - AP, 1985 (Folder 7: 6-8)
  - Personal, 1985 (Folder 7: 9-10)
  - Retirement, 1985 (Folder 7: 11)
  - Personal, 1987-1997 (Folder 7: 12)
  - Stasi Victims, 1991-1997 (Folder 8: 1-2)
  - Stasi Victims - Hugo Kästner, 1992-1996 (Folder 8: 3)
  - Stasi Victims - Günther Müller, 1992-1997. (Folder 8: 4)
  - Stasi Victims - Horst Hölig, 1993-1996 (Folder 8: 5)
  - Stasi Victims - Hohenschönhausen Memorial, 1995 (Folder 8: 6)
  - Stasi Victims - Günther Becker, 1995 (Folder 8: 7)
  - Stasi Victims - Burkhard Günther, 1995 (Folder 8: 8)
  - Stasi Victims - Gottfried Gläser, 1995-1996 (Folder 8: 9)
  - Stasi Victims - Erika Holsten-Warnke, 1995-1996 (Folder 8: 10)
  - Stasi Victims - Heinz Kuhn, 1995-1996 (Folder 8: 11)
  - Stasi Victims - Helga and Günther Jahn, 1995-1997 (Folder 8: 12)
- Photographs, 1960-1979.; 0.2 linear feet (Box 9)
  Consists of photographs and negatives relating to Koehler's work for the Associated Press and on his research. Includes photographs of the Berlin Wall, escapes from East Germany, and of Koehler himself in action as a reporter. Many of the photographs are personal copies of AP photographs.
  - Borders, undated (Folder 9: 1)
  - John Koehler, 1960s-1970s (Folder 9: 2-3)
  - Berlin Wall and escapes, 1960-1965 (Folder 9: 4-6)
  - Berlin photographic negatives, 1961 (Folder 9: 7)
- Stasi Research Material, 1931-2002.; 19.97 linear feet (Box 1-8, 18-50, 52-57)
  Contains clippings, photocopies of East German State Security Ministry (Stasi) documents, post-reunification German government reports, photocopies of United States government documents, and audio and video recordings of interviews conducted by Koehler in the course of his research for Stasi: the Untold Story of the East German Secret Police.
  This series is arranged in five subseries: German Democratic Republic State Security Ministry files, 1931-1993 [bulk 1952-1989]; Federal Republic of Germany reports, 1990-1998; United States government documents, 1943-1997; Interviews and Broadcasts, 1991-1997; Subject files, 1931-2002.
  - East German State Security Ministry Files, 1931-1997, [bulk 1952-1989].; 4.5 linear feet (Box 18-29)
    Photocopies of documents produced by the East German Ministry for State Security (Stasi). Original documents are held by the Bundesbeauftragte für die Unterlagen des Staatssicherheitsdienstes der ehemaligen Deutschen Demokratischen Republik (BStU). Four broad topics (identified by the archivist) are present in the files: international espionage and counterespionage, general Stasi operations, surveillance and repression, and terrorism.
    Koehler's subject-oriented folder titles and thematic organization have been maintained, though folders with similar titles have been grouped to aid research. Where folder titles did not already exist, the archivist has supplied the Stasi Chief Department (Hauptabteilung) that produced the records, document number and a brief description of their contents.
    - International Espionage and Counterespionage
      - Phantom ops, undated (Folder 18: 1)
      - HVA (Intercepted U.S. Transmissions), 1987 (Folder 18: 2)
      - Hauptabteilung III (U.S. Espionage), 1987 (Folder 18: 3)
      - INSCOM conference, 1987 (Folder 18: 4)
      - Recruiting CIA agents, undated (Folder 18: 5)
      - Analysis of BfGA, 1980 (Folder 18: 6)
      - NATO, 1968 (Folder 18: 7)
      - U.S. citizen arrested for espionage, 1967 (Folder 18: 8)
      - Manuals, 1952-1978 (Folder 18: 9)
      - Analysis of political operative responsibilities, 1972 (Folder 18: 10)
      - HVA FBI Analysis, 1977 (Folder 18: 11)
      - Analysis of U.S. covert operations, 1972 (Folder 18: 12)
      - U.S. Military visits, 1950-1957 (Folder 18: 13)
      - Analysis of U.S. economic strategy, 1989 (Folder 18: 14)
      - Analysis of U.S. policy, 1972-1988 (Folder 19: 1-2)
      - Western military intelligence activities, 1989 (Folder 19: 3)
      - Commercial imports, 1984 (Folder 19: 4)
      - U.S. objectives in Berlin, unitdate (Folder 19: 5)
      - U.S.-West German economic ties, 1966 (Folder 19: 6)
      - Hauptabteilung II (Counterespionage), 1966 (Folder 19: 7)
      - Counterespionage Training Manual, 1988 (Folder 19: 8)
      - Counterespionage, 1957-1959 (Folder 19: 9-11)
      - Counterespionage - Tiedke defection, 1988 (Folder 19: 12-14)
      - Latin America agent reports, 1986 (Folder 20: 1)
      - Cuba, 1962-1980 (Folder 20: 2)
      - Hauptabteilung XVIII number 119 (Cuba), 1981-1985 (Folder 20: 3)
      - Nicaragua, 1980-1989 (Folder 20: 4-13)
      - Africa, 1977-1989 (Folder 21: 1-2)
      - Mexico, 1980 (Folder 21: 3)
      - Chile, 1962-1980 (Folder 21: 4-5)
      - HVA structure, 1989-1991 (Folder 21: 6)
      - Anti-Soviet Emigrants, 1956-1959 (Folder 21: 7)
      - Hauptabteilung XVIII number 3463 (Brother Organizations), 1983 (Folder 21: 8)
      - Hauptabteilung XVIII number 11488 (Brother Organizations), 1985-1989 (Folder 21: 9)
      - Cooperating with KGB, 1981-1989 (Folder 21: 10-12)
      - Cooperative agreements (USSR and Hungary), 1981-1986 (Folder 21: 13)
      - KGB Discussions, 1989 (Folder 22: 1)
      - Relationship with KGB, undated (Folder 22: 2)
    - General Stasi Operations
      - Erich Mielke, 1931-1984 (Folder 22: 3)
      - Offiziere im besonderen Einsatz (OibE), 1986 (Folder 22: 4)
      - Hauptabteilung II/19 number 14225 (Wolfgang Seifert), 1972-1989 (Folder 22: 5)
      - Hauptabteilung XX (Surveillance and Informants' Reports), 1987-1989 (Folder 22: 6)
      - Hauptabteilung II and XX (Surveillance and Informants' reports), 1986-1989 (Folder 22: 7)
      - Günther Müller, 1956-1995 (Folder 22: 8-9)
      - Finances, 1978-1990 (Folder 23: 1-2)
    - Surveillance and Repression
      - Hauptabteilung XX number 1386 (Psychiatry), 1976-1989 (Folder 23: 3-7)
      - Electronic surveillance, 1979-1989 (Folder 23: 8)
      - Operation Stoerenfried, 1986-1989 (Folder 23: 9)
      - Recruiting informants, 1979 (Folder 23: 10)
      - Dr. Werner Teske, 1979-1981 (Folder 23: 11-12)
      - Dr. Werner Teske, 1980-1981 (Folder 24: 1-2)
      - Solidarity Committee, 1969-1989 (Folder 24: 3)
      - Jehovah's Witnesses, 1979 (Folder 24: 4)
      - Surveillance of dissidents, 1989 (Folder 24: 5-6)
      - Inoffizielle Mitarbeiter files, 1978-1989 (Folder 24: 7-9)
      - Barczatis and Laurenz executions, 1952-1955 (Folder 24: 10-11)
      - Barczatis and Laurenz executions, 1955 (Folder 25: 1-5)
      - AP Surveillance, 1977-1989 (Folder 25: 6-9)
      - AP Surveillance, 1985-1989 (Folder 26: 1-5)
      - AP Surveillance - Reimold, 1979-1988 (Folder 26: 6-7)
      - AP Surveillance - Schwelz, 1983-1986 (Folder 26: 8)
      - AP Surveillance - Smith, Susan, 1978-1989 (Folder 27: 1-2)
      - Forgeries, 1947-1993 (Folder 27: 3)
      - Linse kidnapping and execution, 1946-1984 (Folder 27: 4-8)
      - Hauptabteilung VIII, Abteilung XX (Horst Erdmann), 1969-1989 (Folder 27: 9)
      - Lothar Fügemann (IM Flamme), 1969-1970, 1997 (Folder 27: 10)
      - Abteilung VI (Leipzig IM Forschung), 1986-1988 (Folder 27: 11)
      - IM Akte A/Teil II (Leipzig Informants' Reports), 1977-1989 (Folder 28: 1-5)
      - Abteilung XXII (IMB Feld), 1985-1989 (Folder 28: 6)
      - Ronald Reagan's Stasi dossier, 1980-1986 (Folder 28: 7)
      - Hauptabteilung XVIII no.11612 (Foreign Visitors), 1981 (Folder 28: 8)
      - Hauptabteilung VIII order 6/78 (Political Operatives), 1978 (Folder 28: 9)
      - Hauptabteilung VIII (Foreign Publishers), 1979 (Folder 28: 10)
      - Hauptabteilung VI no. C118/81 (Analysis of Political Operations), 1981 (Folder 28: 11)
    - Terrorism
      - Iran, 1971-1987 (Folder 29: 1-2)
      - Libya, 1978-1986 (Folder 29: 3)
      - Terror Group Separat, 1984 (Folder 29: 4)
      - Terrorism, 1954-1987 (Folder 29: 5)
  - Federal Republic of Germany Files, 1990-1998.; 4.59 linear feet (Box 29-39)
    Reports, transcripts, press releases, and scholarly articles produced in post-reunification Germany, primarily by the government. Includes articles regarding the process of reunification. Primarily documents the criminal investigation of Stasi activities and resulting trials. Also includes reports summarizing East German government structure and methodology. The agency producing the report has been noted in parenthesis in many cases.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Dokumentation zum Staatsicherheitsdienst der ehemaligen DDR (BfGA), 1990 (Folder 29: 7)
    - Dokumentation zur politischen Justiz in der ehemaligen DDR und Aufarbeitung ihrer Vergangenheit(BfgA), 1991 (Folder 29: 8-10)
    - Zweiter Teilbericht des 1. Untersuchungsausschusses mit einer Darstellung der zum Bereich Kommerzielle Koordinierung gehörenden Unternehmen, 1992 (Folder 30: 1)
    - Erste Beschlußempfehlung (Artikel 44 des Grundgesetzes), 1992 (Folder 30: 2-8)
    - Die Inoffiziellen Mitarbeiter (BStU), 1992 (Folder 31: 1-2)
    - Wolf Indictment, 1992 (Folder 31: 3-5)
    - Indictment of Wagenbreth, Mutz, Rabe, and Michels, 1993 (Folder 31: 6)
    - Indictment of Wagenbreth, Mutz, Rabe, and Michels, 1993 (Folder 32: 1-3)
    - Tätigkeitsberichte des BStU, 1993-1997 (Folder 32: 4)
    - Das Wörterbuch der Staatssicherheit (BF no. 1/93), 1993 (Folder 32: 5)
    - Analysen und Berichte: Zu Wahrnehmung und Interpretation des Rechtsextremismus in der DDR durch das MfS (BF no.1/93), 1993 (Folder 32: 6)
    - Dokumente: Die Organisationsstruktur des Ministeriums für Staatssicherheit (BF), 1993 (Folder 32: 7)
    - Analysen und Berichte: Das Zusammenspiel von Staatssicherheitsdienst und SED nach der Selbstverbrennung des Pfarrers Oskar Brüsewitz aus Rippicha am 18. August 1976 (BF no. 2/93), 1993 (Folder 33: 1)
    - IM Statistik (BF no. 3/93), 1993 (Folder 33: 2)
    - Zweiter Zwischenbericht der Unabhängigen Kommission zur Überprüfung des Vermögens der Parteien und Massenorganisationen der DDR, 1993 (Folder 33: 3)
    - Kratsch indictment, 1993 (Folder 33: 4-6)
    - Vogel indictment, 1993 (Folder 33: 7-10)
    - Vogel indictment, 1993 (Folder 34: 1-4)
    - Beschlußempfehlung, 1993-1994 (Folder 34: 5-6)
    - Beschlußempfehlung und Bericht, 1994 (Folder 34: 7-9)
    - Beschlußempfehlung und Bericht, 1994 (Folder 35: 1-2)
    - Beschlußempfehlung und Bericht - Anhangband, 1994 (Folder 35: 3-6)
    - Beschlußempfehlung und Bericht - Anlageband 1, 1994 (Folder 35: 7-11)
    - Beschlußempfehlung und Bericht - Anlageband 1, 1994 (Folder 36: 1-2)
    - Beschlußempfehlung und Bericht - Anlageband 2, 1994 (Folder 36: 3-9)
    - Beschlußempfehlung und Bericht - Anlageband 3, 1994 (Folder 36: 10-12)
    - Beschlußempfehlung und Bericht - Anlageband 3, 1994 (Folder 37: 1-2)
    - Attorney General press releases, 1991-1994 (Folder 37: 3)
    - Bericht der Enquete-Kommission "Aufarbeitung von Geschichte und Folgen der SED-Diktatur in Deutschland,", 1994 (Folder 37: 4)
    - Zentrale Ermittlungsstelle Regierungs- und Vereinigungskriminalität (ZERV) situation report, 1994 (Folder 37: 5)
    - Offiziere im besonderen Einsatz List, 1994 (Folder 37: 6)
    - Criminal Investigations, 1994 (Folder 37: 7)
    - Dokumente: MfS und Leistungssport (BF no. 1/1994) (Folder 37: 8)
    - Die Hauptamtlichen 1962 (BF no. 1/94), 1994 (Folder 37: 9)
    - Analyse und Berichte: Die Niederschlagung des Prager Frühlings (BF no. 1/94), 1994 (Folder 37: 10)
    - BF informiert: Unter Nutzung der Angst (BF no. 2/1994) (Folder 37: 11)
    - BF informiert: Zu Struktur, Charakter und Bedeutung der Unterlagen des Ministeriums für Staatssicherheit (BF no.3/94), 1994 (Folder 37: 12)
    - BF informiert: Bibliographie zum Staatssicherheitsdienst der DDR (BF no. 4/1994) (Folder 38: 1)
    - BF informiert: Entmachtung und Verfall des Staatssicherheit ein Kapitel aus dem Spätherbst 1989 (BF no. 5/1994) (Folder 38: 2)
    - Analysen und Berichte: Vorbereitung auf den Tag X die geplanten Isolierungslager des MfS (BF no.1/95), 1995 (Folder 38: 3)